ABOUT ME

I am a well-rounded Python developer with over 7 years of experience in data science and web development teams in a variety of industries such as e-commerce, fitness and market research. The common thread has always been to build products that support users to make better sense of their data.

My philosophy: build things right, build the right things, and work in a sustainable way. I care about code quality and testing, releasing small and iterating, practicing open communication and always reflecting on my processes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Senior Software Engineer (self-employed), remote

Delivering quality backend and data processing systems. Key areas:

- Setting up, extending and monitoring cloud infrastructure (AWS, Heroku, Datadog, Docker)
- Django backend development
- Data pipelines, focus on geospatial data (airflow, celery, pandas, pySpark, QGIS)
- Expertise in fair and objective technical interviewing

March 2017 - August 2018

Senior Software Engineer at siroop, Zürich

Worked in the data science and the web development team of a Swiss e-commerce platform with thousands of sales every day.

Full Stack Web development

- Built critical features from scratch (voucher and promotion support, custom brand pages, integration of analytics tracking) using Django, Flask and RESTful services
- Extended existing functionality (product pages, CMS service and payment system) practicing TDD and pair programming
- Optimized test running time, local deployments with dockercompose and other aspects of the day to day development process
- Updated and deployed new AWS infrastructure (lambdas, Kinesis stream, DynamoDB) using Terraform
- Participated and led agile ceremonies (stand-ups, retrospectives)
- Acted as deputy team lead for a team of 7 and mentored more junior engineers

Data Engineering

- Launched personalized product recommendations to production
- · Worked closely with data scientists to build a tool library
- Introduced and set up airflow as a pipeline manager for the recurring jobs
- Introduced and set up databricks as a development environment
- Troubleshooting for scaling and cluster issues



WORK EXPERIENCE CONTD.

November 2015 - February 2017

Lead Data Engineer at Tracktics GmbH, Zürich

Responsible for overseeing the extracting of insights from GPS and sensor data, collected from a tracker worn by football players in the field.

- Built the production data pipeline. It automatically processed the raw data (various stages, eg: MATLAB binary, Jupyter notebooks and python modules, chained together with celery)
- Launched various additional tools (heatmap generator, football pitch locator) to production
- Designed and oversaw the collection of test data to evaluate our algorithms
- Built evaluation into the data pipeline (in a way that externals could use it, and internals could easily create new report templates for new metrics)
- Built a library of common functionality together with the data scientists and mentored junior engineers

SEPTEMBER 2013 - JUNE 2015

Software Engineer at Teralytics AG, Zürich

Worked as a software engineer, extracting insights from mobile phone data and supporting my colleagues to do so.

- Created data pipelines to go from raw data to automatically updating web dashboards in production
- Created interactive visualizations of geospatial data (using PostGIS, d3, QGIS) for our customers
- Contributed to (and became co-maintainer) of an open source tool to visualize geotemporal data
- Built a library to unify access to diverse data sources

SELECTED CONFERENCES AND ARTICLES

- 2017 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference:
 Patterns for Collaboration between Data Scientists
 and Software Engineers
 video | article
- 2016 Published reflections on the future of Data Pipelines and the future of Python for Data Science
- 2015 Tutorial (Python): Exploring a UFO sightings dataset
- 2015 Article: Common mistakes with Python and Big Data
- 2015 Workshop on visualizing geotemporal data
- 2014 Presented published paper at VLDB 2014
- 2014 Speaker at PyData Berlin conference on Mall Analytics (from prototype to product)

EDUCATION

2011 – 2013 **Master of Science**

COMPUTER SCIENCE ETH Zürich

GPA: 5.5/6 (also received scholarship)

2007 – 2011 Bachelor of Science

COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Athens

GPA: 9.3/10 - Top graduate in fall 2011

SELECTED FREELANCE WORK

DevOps and Backend Developer for Gilytics, remote

Managing deployments of GIS on AWS. Docker, terraform, Django Rest Framework.

Data Integrations for OpenHumans, remote

Built data integrations between Open Humans and GoogleFit, and Open Humans and Github.

The data integration apps are hosted on heroku and periodically sync activity data of the user to Open Humans. Uses Oauth2 for both websites to ensure withdrawable consent of the user. The synced data is then provided and visualized to the user in a Jupyter notebook dashboard or for them to download.

Node Developer for SignedBlock, remote

Extended and dockerized a program for live collection of data from the cryptocurrency market.

QGIS Plugin Developer for OpenGis.ch, Zürich

Responsible for developing Python plugins for geospatial data management.

Python and Data Engineering Tutor, remote

Micro-consulting via codementor.io on several data science/engineering projects.

Mentor at Andela, remote

Mentored junior programmers in Python, testing and programming patterns to prepare them for working remotely.

Data Consultant for New Incentives, Zürich

Created a data pipeline in Scala to sync data daily across mobile devices and Google spreadsheets.

Software Engineering Intern at Google, Zürich

Migrated a feature of Youtube Analytics to the new backend.

LANGUAGES

English, German and Spanish in full professional capacity. Greek as mother tongue, some French.

Personal Interests

Painting (have some professional training), Social Science, Traveling. I have combined my thinking/practice as a programmer with those of being an artist to create a Drawing for Techies Workshop, which I have run multiple times in Switzerland, Germany and the UK.